<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quantification on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/quantification/</link><description>Recent content in Quantification on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:18:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/quantification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Credible Estimates and Open Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/blair-institute/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:18:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/blair-institute/</guid><description>Somewhere on social media I encountered the recent story that the Tony Blair Institute for Global Change, (a large, avowedly centrist think tank created by Tony Blair), put out a report estimating the potential impact of AI on jobs in the public service, but that ironically, they arrived at their estimates by basically just asking GPT-4. While this does have a certain kind of poetry to it, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly what we think of as a reputable methodology.</description></item><item><title>Counting Deaths</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/counting-deaths/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 17:24:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/counting-deaths/</guid><description>Although morbid, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to read a recent article in the NYT about efforts in Sierra Leone to use &amp;ldquo;electronic autopsies&amp;rdquo; in a large scale attempt at counting deaths. According to the article, this undertaking is part of a broader effort at data collection, including questions on age, religion, marital status, etc. The novelty, it seems, is in trying to be thorough with respect to what people have died of (including extensive questions about symptoms), even though this information is being collected potentially long after the fact.</description></item></channel></rss>