<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reproducibility on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/reproducibility/</link><description>Recent content in reproducibility on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 10:42:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/reproducibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Gradual Disappearance of Twitter</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/twitter-immolation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 10:42:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/twitter-immolation/</guid><description>It was recently reported by inews.co.uk that Twitter is going to start charging academic researchers and institution $42,000/month if they want to maintain their current level of expansive access to data, and &amp;ndash; more significantly &amp;ndash; require that they delete all Twitter data from their archives if they do not. I&amp;rsquo;d heard rumors that this might be happening a few weeks ago, but the iNews article is the first independent reporting that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen about it.</description></item><item><title>Confidence in Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/confidence-in-science/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 09:20:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/confidence-in-science/</guid><description>I’ve been thinking recently about the role of confidence in science, and how long beliefs can persist simply because everyone else seems to believe them. Coincidentally, Andrew Gelman posted about this two days ago, responding to comments from a biologist about how the replication crisis had not been a major problem in biology. Her argument was that this was because biology is a &amp;ldquo;cumulative science&amp;rdquo;. By this she meant that when something important gets published, it is often the kind of discovery that people want to use immediately.</description></item><item><title>AI Dermatology: Part 2</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 16:26:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-2/</guid><description>​In the last post, I discussed the possible broader implications of Google&amp;rsquo;s recent foray into making an AI dermatology tool. In this follow up post, I want to focus on the research behind the product announcement, bringing a slightly critical eye.</description></item><item><title>Reproducibility in Art and Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 20:43:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</guid><description>Marking the beginning of a new partnership between Rhizome and the Google Cultural Institute, the Rhizome blog recently published a conversation between Dragan Espenschied, Rhizome’s preservation director, and Vint Cerf, Google’s Chief Internet Evangelist. In addition to bringing together two people with among the coolest job titles ever, it got me thinking about some similarities between art and science when it comes to the issue of reproduction.
The main thrust of the conversation is about the difficulty of preserving internet art.</description></item></channel></rss>