<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reproducibility on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/reproducibility/</link><description>Recent content in Reproducibility on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 10:00:26 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/reproducibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ChatGPT Prompt Speculations</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/chatgpt-prompt-speculations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 10:00:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/chatgpt-prompt-speculations/</guid><description>In a recent tweet that went viral, Dylan Patel claimed to have discovered or revealed the ChatGPT prompt, using a simple hack. The tweet included a link to a text file on pastebin and a screenshot of that same text with newlines removed. More interestingly, the author suggested in a reply that anyone could replicate this finding, and a subsequent tweet included a video of ChatGPT generating text in response to the same trick. That, however, is where things get somewhat strange.</description></item><item><title>University of Michigan's New AI Tools</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/michigan-gpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 21:04:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/michigan-gpt/</guid><description>Just before the start of the fall semester, the University of Michigan announced that it was launching a new suite of tools, all focused on &amp;ldquo;generative AI&amp;rdquo;, (although so far limited to language models), which will be available to all students, faculty, and staff. This post provides a preliminary exploration of the new offerings.</description></item><item><title>The Gradual Disappearance of Twitter</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/twitter-immolation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 10:42:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/twitter-immolation/</guid><description>It was recently reported by inews.co.uk that Twitter is going to start charging academic researchers and institution $42,000/month if they want to maintain their current level of expansive access to data, and &amp;ndash; more significantly &amp;ndash; require that they delete all Twitter data from their archives if they do not. I&amp;rsquo;d heard rumors that this might be happening a few weeks ago, but the iNews article is the first independent reporting that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen about it.</description></item><item><title>Confidence in Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/confidence-in-science/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 09:20:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/confidence-in-science/</guid><description>I’ve been thinking recently about the role of confidence in science, and how long beliefs can persist simply because everyone else seems to believe them. Coincidentally, Andrew Gelman posted about this two days ago, responding to comments from a biologist about how the replication crisis had not been a major problem in biology. Her argument was that this was because biology is a &amp;ldquo;cumulative science&amp;rdquo;. By this she meant that when something important gets published, it is often the kind of discovery that people want to use immediately.</description></item><item><title>AI Dermatology: Part 2</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 16:26:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-2/</guid><description>​In the last post, I discussed the possible broader implications of Google&amp;rsquo;s recent foray into making an AI dermatology tool. In this follow up post, I want to focus on the research behind the product announcement, bringing a slightly critical eye.</description></item><item><title>Reproducibility in Art and Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 20:43:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</guid><description>Marking the beginning of a new partnership between Rhizome and the Google Cultural Institute, the Rhizome blog recently published a conversation between Dragan Espenschied, Rhizome’s preservation director, and Vint Cerf, Google’s Chief Internet Evangelist. In addition to bringing together two people with among the coolest job titles ever, it got me thinking about some similarities between art and science when it comes to the issue of reproduction.
The main thrust of the conversation is about the difficulty of preserving internet art.</description></item></channel></rss>