<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>privacy on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in privacy on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:32:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI Dermatology: Part 1</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:32:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-1/</guid><description>Midway through last year Google announced a new foray into the medical technology space, sharing that it was developing an &amp;ldquo;AI-powered dermatology assist tool&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;a phone-based app that would allow users to take photos of skin lesions and retrieve information about relevant medical conditions from the web. Similar apps already exist, but it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that a comparable effort by Google is likely to have much more significant effects on how people interact with the medical system, their personal data, and even their own bodies.</description></item><item><title>On the Perils of Automated Face Recognition</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/face-recognition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:59:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/face-recognition/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Bertillon,_Alphonse,_fiche_anthropom%C3%A9trique_recto-verso.jpg">&lt;img src="../../img/face-recognition/bertillon.jpeg"
alt="Anthropometric data sheet (both sides) of Alphonse Bertillon (1853–1914)."/>&lt;/a>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Anthropometric data sheet (both sides) of Alphonse Bertillon (1853–1914).&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For anyone who has been paying attention, it will not have gone unnoticed that the past year has seen a dramatic expansion in the use of face recognition technology, including at schools, border crossing, and interactions with the police. Most recently, &lt;a href="https://news.delta.com/delta-unveils-first-biometric-terminal-us-atlanta-next-stop-detroit">Delta announced&lt;/a> that some passengers in Atlanta will be able to check in and go through security using only their face as identification. Most news coverage of this announcement emphasized the supposed convenience, efficiency, and technical novelty, while underplaying any potential hazards. In fact, however, the combination of widely available images, the ability to build on existing infrastructure, and a legal landscape that places very few restrictions on recording, means that face recognition represents a unique threat to privacy that should concern us greatly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy in Context</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/privacy-in-context/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 23:09:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/privacy-in-context/</guid><description>Although it was not the largest of its kind, or the most invasive, or even particularly surprising, the recent Cambridge Analytica scandal produced a surprisingly large amount of outrage and commentary. If nothing else, it was yet another reminder that we have gradually slipped into a regime where certain aspects of our privacy that could once be taken for granted are now long gone. Are people concerned? Is this something we should be worried about?</description></item></channel></rss>