<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>art on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/art/</link><description>Recent content in art on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:59:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infinitely Wide Culture</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/infinitely-wide-culture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:59:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/infinitely-wide-culture/</guid><description>A lot of this is still unresolved in my mind, but I think there is something interesting happening at the intersection of generative AI, art, style, and entertainment. Rather than letting it gestate until more fully formed, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d just post some preliminary thoughts and come back to this at some later date.
The main reason I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about this now is the ongoing debate about how generative AI will impact creative fields, such as writing and design (as well as white collar jobs more broadly).</description></item><item><title>Tightly-woven Cultural Commentary</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:57:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</guid><description>I recently started listening to the Art of the Score podcast, which does an amazing job of unpacking movie soundtracks in depth, beginning with Raiders of the Lost Ark in the first episode. Like most such explorations of music, however, it ultimately leaves me wanting something that I&amp;rsquo;ve long thought there should be much more of&amp;mdash;namely, more tightly interwoven cultural commentary, especially for music. As I will describe below, I&amp;rsquo;m broadly interested in different ways of combining context, commentary, and criticism with the thing being commented on or critiqued.</description></item><item><title>Refik Anadol</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 11:05:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</guid><description>Last week&amp;rsquo;s speaker in the Penny Stamps Speaker Series was Refik Anadol, one of the most successful artists working primarily with AI, data, and visualization. Over a decade or so, Anadol has produced work in collaboration with organizations and venues like the LA Philharmonic, Gaudi&amp;rsquo;s Casa Batlló, the Exosphere in Las Vegas, and the Museum of Modern Art in New York.
The lecture he gave was basically a review of his body of work, and that of his art and design studio, which is comprised of about 20 people.</description></item><item><title>Reproducibility in Art and Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 20:43:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</guid><description>Marking the beginning of a new partnership between Rhizome and the Google Cultural Institute, the Rhizome blog recently published a conversation between Dragan Espenschied, Rhizome’s preservation director, and Vint Cerf, Google’s Chief Internet Evangelist. In addition to bringing together two people with among the coolest job titles ever, it got me thinking about some similarities between art and science when it comes to the issue of reproduction.
The main thrust of the conversation is about the difficulty of preserving internet art.</description></item></channel></rss>