<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visualization on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/visualization/</link><description>Recent content in Visualization on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:57:32 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tightly-woven Cultural Commentary</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:57:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</guid><description>I recently started listening to the Art of the Score podcast, which does an amazing job of unpacking movie soundtracks in depth, beginning with Raiders of the Lost Ark in the first episode. Like most such explorations of music, however, it ultimately leaves me wanting something that I&amp;rsquo;ve long thought there should be much more of&amp;mdash;namely, more tightly interwoven cultural commentary, especially for music. As I will describe below, I&amp;rsquo;m broadly interested in different ways of combining context, commentary, and criticism with the thing being commented on or critiqued.</description></item><item><title>Altair vs. Bokeh (part 2)</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/altair_vs_bokeh_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 18:17:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/altair_vs_bokeh_2/</guid><description>In the first part of this series, I used a basic bar plot to illustrate the differences between Altair and Bokeh in terms of defaults, chart configuration, and syntactic style. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll get into some of the more substantive differences, including more complicated chart types, combining plots, basic interactivity, and how to deploy the output online. Note that this is not intended to be a systematic comparison, but rather more of a preliminary exploration of the options.</description></item><item><title>Refik Anadol</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 11:05:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</guid><description>Last week&amp;rsquo;s speaker in the Penny Stamps Speaker Series was Refik Anadol, one of the most successful artists working primarily with AI, data, and visualization. Over a decade or so, Anadol has produced work in collaboration with organizations and venues like the LA Philharmonic, Gaudi&amp;rsquo;s Casa Batlló, the Exosphere in Las Vegas, and the Museum of Modern Art in New York.
The lecture he gave was basically a review of his body of work, and that of his art and design studio, which is comprised of about 20 people.</description></item><item><title>Altair vs. Bokeh (part 1)</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/altair_vs_bokeh_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 18:17:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/altair_vs_bokeh_1/</guid><description>This is the first of what I hope will be a series of posts comparing Altair and Bokeh. Both are actively supported python packages for making interactive visualizations. This post will only scratch the surface, but is intended to show the basic differences in how they approach creating visualizations.</description></item></channel></rss>