<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Natasha-Dow-Schüll on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/natasha-dow-sch%C3%BCll/</link><description>Recent content in Natasha-Dow-Schüll on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 22:07:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/natasha-dow-sch%C3%BCll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chatbot Roulette</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/freysa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 22:07:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/freysa/</guid><description>&lt;p>There was some excitement online recently around &lt;a href="https://x.com/jarrodWattsDev/status/1862299845710757980">&amp;ldquo;Freysa&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>, a contest which combined large language models (LLMs) with some sort of blockchain technology. The basic idea was for participants to interact with an LLM to try to get it to do a thing that it had been instructed not to do. The trick was that the cost of each attempt increased after every submission (up to some maximum), as did the potential reward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sociotechnical Considerations</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sociotechnical-considerations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:42:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sociotechnical-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p>A whole genre of podcasts seems to have emerged recently, taking the shape of interviews with CEOs of AI companies, or similar. Although I have not listened to many of these, they mostly seem to be pretty abysmal, both because of the amount of hype they involve, and due to the lack of meaningful specifics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, of the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, the recent &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/12/podcasts/transcript-ezra-klein-interviews-dario-amodei.html">interview with Dario Amodei of Anthropic on the Ezra Klein Show&lt;/a> seems to me to be vastly better than the average. In part, this is because Klein is a smart, curious, and well informed interviewer, who asks a lot of the right questions, and pushes for details when responses get too mushy. In this case, it also helps that Amodei seems much more straightforwardly honest about limitations than most spokespeople in similar positions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>