<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>archives on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/archives/</link><description>Recent content in archives on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 10:42:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/archives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Slow Death of Twitter as a Natural Resource</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/twitter-immolation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 10:42:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/twitter-immolation/</guid><description>It was recently reported by inews.co.uk that Twitter is going to start charging academic researchers and institution $42,000/month if they want to maintain their current level of expansive access to data, and &amp;ndash; more significantly &amp;ndash; require that they delete all Twitter data from their archives if they do not. I&amp;rsquo;d heard rumors that this might be happening a few weeks ago, but this article is the first independent reporting that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on this topic.</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT and Sociotechnical Instability</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/chatgpt_and_instability/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 13:04:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/chatgpt_and_instability/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this before, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth remembering that almost nothing in sociotechnical systems is guaranteed to remain stable for very long. We&amp;rsquo;ve recently had two great examples of this, with the first being the changes to Twitter, and the second being ChatGPT (and, by extension, the new Bing).
In the first case, a platform which had long seemed relatively static, (especially compared to all the rest), rather suddenly changed hands, which led to major changes in what it delivered.</description></item><item><title>Counting Deaths</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/counting-deaths/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 17:24:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/counting-deaths/</guid><description>Although morbid, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to read a recent article in the NYT about efforts in Sierra Leone to use &amp;ldquo;electronic autopsies&amp;rdquo; in a large scale attempt at counting deaths. According to the article, this undertaking is part of a broader effort at data collection, including questions on age, religion, marital status, etc. The novelty, it seems, is in trying to be thorough with respect to what people have died of (including extensive questions about symptoms), even though this information is being collected potentially long after the fact.</description></item><item><title>Stability and Change</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/stability/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 17:40:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/stability/</guid><description>One of the biggest frustrations with software is that things are constantly changing. From operating systems to apps to web interfaces, things rarely remain the same for very long, especially for users of Windows or MacOS.
There are many reasons for this of course. For decades, hardware has continued to improve at a steady rate, and so software is constantly being rewritten to take advantage of the latest capabilities. Moreover, the incredibly sloppy standard for software quality and reliability (compared to traditional engineering disciplines) means that even the most professional software is shipped with massive numbers of bugs and vulnerabilities, which constantly need to be patched.</description></item><item><title>Emergent Archives</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/emergent-archives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 22:12:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/emergent-archives/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="../../img/emergent-archives/archives.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It’s fascinating to think about how much we give to the internet, and sometimes, how much it gives back. In my mind, there is a fairly direct historical connection between self-archiving practices from a couple of decades ago (keeping a diary, making photo albums, writing letters, etc.), to all the more recent variations on this idea (status updates, tweets, photo feeds, etc.). The difference is arguably in how much of the background work is taken care of for us, and the fact that we now make so much of this information public or semi-public. While many have explored the implications of this for privacy, security, and surveillance, there is another aspect that gets less attention: the automatic creation of our own archives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Montage as Archive</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/montage-as-archive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 22:07:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/montage-as-archive/</guid><description>I was recently reminded of Christian Marclay’s The Clock&amp;mdash;a 24 hour film made up of thousands of short film clips, carefully edited together such that (when properly synchronized) the time depicted in each moment of film corresponds to the current time in the world. I’ve never seen it, and sadly only a few copies exist, but I think it’s a fascinating example of a kind of archival art.
When you hear the description, you might think of it as just a kind of a gimmick, one which would not reward actual viewing.</description></item><item><title>The Self-Archiving machine</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/self-archiving-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 20:47:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/self-archiving-machine/</guid><description>What lies in store for this post? As I write this, it exists in a strange space — not yet public, yet already part of an archive, of a kind. Perhaps it cannot yet even be properly called a post, (since it has not yet been posted), and yet it is there for me to read and edit, part of my collection of unpublished stubs, stored on the Medium servers along with who knows what metadata.</description></item></channel></rss>