<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Measurement on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/measurement/</link><description>Recent content in Measurement on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 16:51:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/measurement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bespoke Navigation</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/bespoke-navigation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 16:51:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/bespoke-navigation/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do this, but I recently did a short bike trip in Michigan, and I thought I would write a brief post about it, in part because it cued various other ideas which have a more direct connection to the kinds of things I normally write about here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ChatGPT Hobbyists</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/mcgee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 10:42:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/mcgee/</guid><description>&lt;p>ChatGPT has understandably garnered a huge amount of attention from all corners of academia, from philosophy to economics. One of the more quixotic examples I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered recently is &lt;a href="https://www.robertwmcgee.com/about/">Robert W. McGee&lt;/a>, and his many papers on this topic, such as &lt;a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4359405">&amp;ldquo;Is Chat Gpt Biased Against Conservatives? An Empirical Study&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A professor of accounting at Fayetteville University, McGee&amp;rsquo;s biography reads as something like a Marvel Cinematic Universe version of a nerdy academic supervillain. In addition to having published 59 non-fiction books, McGee apparently holds 23 academic degrees, including 13 doctorates, as well as being a world champion in various martial arts, such as Taekwondo and Tai Chi.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modular Domain Adaptation</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/modular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:16:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/modular/</guid><description>Despite their limitations, off-the-shelf models are still quite widely used by computational social science researchers for measuring various properties of text, including both lexicons, like LIWC, and cloud-based APIs, like Perspective API. The approach of using an off-the-shelf model has some definite advantages, including standardization and reproducibility, but such models may not be reliable when applied to a domain that differs from the ones on which they were developed&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>