<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>History on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/history/</link><description>Recent content in History on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 22:07:35 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Montage as Archive</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/montage-as-archive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 22:07:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/montage-as-archive/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was recently reminded of Christian Marclay’s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Clock_(2010_film)">&lt;em>The Clock&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&amp;mdash;a 24 hour film made up of thousands of short film clips, carefully edited together such that (when properly synchronized) the time depicted in each moment of film corresponds to the current time in the world. I’ve never seen it, and sadly only a few copies exist, but I think it’s a fascinating example of a kind of archival art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you hear the description, you might think of it as just a kind of a gimmick, one which would not reward actual viewing. However, based on the (bootlegged) clips that are &lt;a href="https://kottke.org/13/06/about-an-hour-of-christian-marclays-the-clock">available online&lt;/a> and reports from various people who have seen it, it apparently achieves much more. To be clear, although many of the scenes involve a shot of some sort of time piece (thereby establishing the time in the source film), the composition is not so simple as just finding and assembling shots of clocks. Rather, we see a slice in time, sometimes with intercutting between films. As a result, common patterns quickly emerge: in the morning we get people waking up. In the evening, we see people eating dinner and attending parties, etc. This is interesting because what is shown in films bears some relation to what happens in the real world; even if it ends up being a distorted or idealized reflection, this certainly tells us something about how Hollywood depicts society, and by implication, something about society itself.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>