<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Culture on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/culture/</link><description>Recent content in Culture on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 19:34:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is a Podcast?</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sporc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 19:34:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sporc/</guid><description>What is a podcast? I expect we all have our own slightly idiosyncratic answer to that question. For me, podcasts are defined partly by some software I use on my phone that regularly downloads audio files from various feeds, which I periodically listen to, often as I&amp;rsquo;m doing other things. Most of these recordings feature two or more people engaged in a long-form conversation. Some of these take the form of interviews, in which a regular host interviews a rotating series of guests. Others feature rotating subsets of the same group of hosts, talking together about various issues. A few shoes, like Hardcore History, are just long monologues, not so different from an audiobook.</description></item><item><title>The OpenAI Library</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/openai-library/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:52:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/openai-library/</guid><description>The New York Times recently ran a brief article about the reading room in OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s office in San Francisco. The article was heavy on images and light on text, but the overall theme was the tension between the company&amp;rsquo;s GPT models&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->—&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->which have been trained on vast swaths of human culture, and are therefore able to regurgitate, remix, and approximate it&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->—&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->versus embracing the design and aesthetic trappings of a traditional library reading room. The article mentioned a handful of books that could be found in the OpenAI library, but many more were clearly visible in the photographs that accompanied it.</description></item><item><title>Infinitely Wide Culture</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/infinitely-wide-culture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:59:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/infinitely-wide-culture/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of this is still unresolved in my mind, but I think there is something interesting happening at the intersection of generative AI, art, style, and entertainment. Rather than letting it gestate until more fully formed, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d just post some preliminary thoughts and come back to this at some later date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main reason I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about this now is the ongoing debate about how generative AI will impact creative fields, such as writing and design (as well as white collar jobs more broadly). Arguably there have already been some pretty dramatic effects, such as the sci-fi magazine &lt;em>Clarkesworld&lt;/em> being &lt;a href="https://neil-clarke.com/a-concerning-trend/">suddenly overwhelmed&lt;/a> by spammy submissions. At the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know the extent to which these disruptions may end up being transient phenomena that broader systems will adapt to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tightly-woven Cultural Commentary</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:57:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently started listening to the &lt;a href="https://www.artofthescore.com.au/">Art of the Score&lt;/a> podcast, which does an amazing job of unpacking movie soundtracks in depth, beginning with Raiders of the Lost Ark in the first episode. Like most such explorations of music, however, it ultimately leaves me wanting something that I&amp;rsquo;ve long thought there should be much more of&amp;mdash;namely, more tightly interwoven cultural commentary, especially for music. As I will describe below, I&amp;rsquo;m broadly interested in different ways of combining context, commentary, and criticism with the thing being commented on or critiqued.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>