<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>artificial-intelligence on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/artificial-intelligence/</link><description>Recent content in artificial-intelligence on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 11:05:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Refik Anadol</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 11:05:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</guid><description>Last week&amp;rsquo;s speaker in the Penny Stamps Speaker Series was Refik Anadol, one of the most successful artists working primarily with AI, data, and visualization. Over a decade or so, Anadol has produced work in collaboration with organizations and venues like the LA Philharmonic, Gaudi&amp;rsquo;s Casa Batlló, the Exosphere in Las Vegas, and the Museum of Modern Art in New York.
The lecture he gave was basically a review of his body of work, and that of his art and design studio, which is comprised of about 20 people.</description></item><item><title>AI, software, and governance</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-software-governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 18:48:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-software-governance/</guid><description>In a recent article covering the FTX collapse, the New York Times described large language models (LLMs) as &amp;ldquo;an increasingly powerful breed of A.I. that can write tweets, emails and blog posts and even generate computer programs.&amp;rdquo; There is a lot that we could pick apart in this definition (e.g., what makes LLMs part of a &amp;ldquo;breed&amp;rdquo;, what distinguishes the ability to write an email as opposed to a blog post, etc.), but for the moment I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus on the term &amp;ldquo;A.I.&amp;rdquo; (henceforth &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo;). Referring to LLMs as an example of AI is certainly not atypical. Indeed, it increasingly seems like LLMs have become one of the modern canonical examples of this concept. But why is it that we think of these systems as members of this category? And how much rhetorical work is being done by referring to LLMs as a type of &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo;, as opposed to &amp;ldquo;models&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;programs&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;systems&amp;rdquo;, or other similar categories?</description></item></channel></rss>