<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stability on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/stability/</link><description>Recent content in Stability on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:59:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/stability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infinitely Wide Culture</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/infinitely-wide-culture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 15:59:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/infinitely-wide-culture/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of this is still unresolved in my mind, but I think there is something interesting happening at the intersection of generative AI, art, style, and entertainment. Rather than letting it gestate until more fully formed, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d just post some preliminary thoughts and come back to this at some later date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main reason I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about this now is the ongoing debate about how generative AI will impact creative fields, such as writing and design (as well as white collar jobs more broadly). Arguably there have already been some pretty dramatic effects, such as the sci-fi magazine &lt;em>Clarkesworld&lt;/em> being &lt;a href="https://neil-clarke.com/a-concerning-trend/">suddenly overwhelmed&lt;/a> by spammy submissions. At the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know the extent to which these disruptions may end up being transient phenomena that broader systems will adapt to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stability and Change</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/stability/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 17:40:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/stability/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the biggest frustrations with software is that things are constantly changing. From operating systems to apps to web interfaces, things rarely remain the same for very long, especially for users of Windows or MacOS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many reasons for this of course. For decades, hardware has continued to improve at a steady rate, and so software is constantly being rewritten to take advantage of the latest capabilities. Moreover, the incredibly sloppy standard for software quality and reliability (compared to traditional engineering disciplines) means that even the most professional software is shipped with massive numbers of bugs and vulnerabilities, which constantly need to be patched. This is a particularly large problem in institutional settings which are not set up for this pace of updates; some of the worst effects of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/12/15630354/nhs-hospitals-ransomware-hack-wannacry-bitcoin">WannaCry&lt;/a> ransomware attack, for example, were on hospitals that were still using hopelessly out of date Windows machines.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>