<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Science on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/science/</link><description>Recent content in Science on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:42:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sociotechnical Considerations</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sociotechnical-considerations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:42:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sociotechnical-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p>A whole genre of podcasts seems to have emerged recently, taking the shape of interviews with CEOs of AI companies, or similar. Although I have not listened to many of these, they mostly seem to be pretty abysmal, both because of the amount of hype they involve, and due to the lack of meaningful specifics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, of the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, the recent &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/12/podcasts/transcript-ezra-klein-interviews-dario-amodei.html">interview with Dario Amodei of Anthropic on the Ezra Klein Show&lt;/a> seems to me to be vastly better than the average. In part, this is because Klein is a smart, curious, and well informed interviewer, who asks a lot of the right questions, and pushes for details when responses get too mushy. In this case, it also helps that Amodei seems much more straightforwardly honest about limitations than most spokespeople in similar positions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tightly-woven Cultural Commentary</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:57:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interwoven_commentary/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently started listening to the &lt;a href="https://www.artofthescore.com.au/">Art of the Score&lt;/a> podcast, which does an amazing job of unpacking movie soundtracks in depth, beginning with Raiders of the Lost Ark in the first episode. Like most such explorations of music, however, it ultimately leaves me wanting something that I&amp;rsquo;ve long thought there should be much more of&amp;mdash;namely, more tightly interwoven cultural commentary, especially for music. As I will describe below, I&amp;rsquo;m broadly interested in different ways of combining context, commentary, and criticism with the thing being commented on or critiqued.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Report from FAccT 2022</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/facct-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 12:59:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/facct-2022/</guid><description>The fifth iteration of FAccT (the ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency) was held earlier this month (June 21–24) in Seoul, South Korea. More than just a hybrid conference, this was actually a full in-person conference, combined with a full on-line conference. These happened in parallel, with virtual sessions starting before and continuing after the in-person component each day. Around 500 people attended in person, with another 500 participating remotely.</description></item><item><title>Confidence in Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/confidence-in-science/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 09:20:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/confidence-in-science/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been thinking recently about the role of confidence in science, and how long beliefs can persist simply because everyone else seems to believe them. Coincidentally, Andrew Gelman &lt;a href="https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/2022/03/04/biology-as-a-cumulative-science-and-the-relevance-of-this-idea-to-replication/">posted&lt;/a> about this two days ago, responding to comments from a biologist about how the replication crisis had not been a major problem in biology. Her argument was that this was because biology is a &amp;ldquo;cumulative science&amp;rdquo;. By this she meant that when something important gets published, it is often the kind of discovery that people want to use immediately. If the original claims was wrong, people will quickly figure it out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AI Dermatology: Part 2</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 16:26:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-2/</guid><description>​In the last post, I discussed the possible broader implications of Google&amp;rsquo;s recent foray into making an AI dermatology tool. In this follow up post, I want to focus on the research behind the product announcement, bringing a slightly critical eye.</description></item><item><title>The case for professional critics in science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/science-critics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 21:24:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/science-critics/</guid><description>&lt;p>In many areas of science, there is an increasingly urgent unmet need, a role that could be simultaneously fascinating, rewarding, and potential remunerative. It is a role that already exists in various forms, but which could be made into something much more potent, especially if forces converged to make it more prominent. I am talking, of course, about the professional science critic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the popular imagination, science operates something like a priesthood: scientists enter elite institutions as novices and emerge years later as full-fledged representatives of The Truth. Along the way, they are trained to be experts and professionals in their subject, to excel in action as well as in thought, and to sacrifice their worldly interests for the sake of their calling. The scholarly journals and peer review process are imagined to operate like an ecumenical council, guiding and filtering the thoughts of the broader community of the devout, and only allowing to pass what is deemed to be true and useful and good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reproducibility in Art and Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 20:43:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marking the beginning of a new &lt;a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2017/may/30/rhizome-google-partnership/">partnership&lt;/a> between Rhizome and the Google Cultural Institute, the Rhizome blog recently published a &lt;a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2017/may/30/preservation-by-accident-is-not-a-plan/">conversation&lt;/a> between Dragan Espenschied, Rhizome’s preservation director, and Vint Cerf, Google’s Chief Internet Evangelist. In addition to bringing together two people with among the coolest job titles ever, it got me thinking about some similarities between art and science when it comes to the issue of reproduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main thrust of the conversation is about the difficulty of preserving internet art. In particular, works such as &lt;a href="https://anthology.rhizome.org/the-web-stalker">The Web Stalker&lt;/a> were often made in a particular context, intended to be performances of a sort, and which depended on the existence of a certain technical infrastructure, including a particular operating system, a particular input device, an internet connection, and accompanying protocols. Part of the conversation relates to the fact that it’s actually very difficult to maintain or recreate every single thing that is required in order for a modern viewer to have the exact same experience as when it was first created. Nevertheless, Dragan argues, there is still value in preserving part of the experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>