<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zach-Leiberman on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/zach-leiberman/</link><description>Recent content in Zach-Leiberman on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 11:05:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/zach-leiberman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Refik Anadol</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 11:05:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/refik-anadol/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week&amp;rsquo;s speaker in the &lt;a href="https://stamps.umich.edu/penny-stamps-speaker-series">Penny Stamps Speaker Series&lt;/a> was &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Refik_Anadol">Refik Anadol&lt;/a>, one of the most successful artists working primarily with AI, data, and visualization. Over a decade or so, Anadol has produced work in collaboration with organizations and venues like the &lt;a href="https://refikanadol.com/works/visions-of-america-ameriques/">LA Philharmonic&lt;/a>, Gaudi&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://refikanadol.com/works/living-architecture-casa-batllo/">Casa Batlló&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://refikanadol.com/works/machine-hallucinations-sphere/">the Exosphere&lt;/a> in Las Vegas, and &lt;a href="https://refikanadol.com/works/unsupervised/">the Museum of Modern Art&lt;/a> in New York.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lecture he gave was basically a review of his body of work, and that of his art and design studio, which is comprised of about 20 people. The earlier projects he showed mostly took the form of massive scale &lt;a href="https://refikanadol.com/works/quadrature/">light projections&lt;/a> on the sides of buildings, which could give the impression of a totally different texture or form. More recent work tended to use data driven visualizations, abstracting some sort of data into visual patterns displayed on a wall, building, or screen. Many of these also made use of what appeared to be procedural animations to create the impression of three dimensionality and motion.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>