<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine-learning on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine-learning on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 21:27:37 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Representational Power</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/representational-power/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 21:27:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/representational-power/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/View_from_the_Window_at_Le_Gras">&lt;img src="../../img/representational-power//plate.jpeg"
alt="The original plate of “View from the Window at Le Gras”, a heliograph made by Nicéphore Niépce around 1827."/>&lt;/a>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>The original plate of “View from the Window at Le Gras”, a heliograph made by Nicéphore Niépce around 1827.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Although it isn’t normally thought of in these terms, taking a photograph involves recording a four-dimensional block of space-time and projecting it down to a two-dimensional representation. With sufficiently sensitive material (and a fast enough shutter), one can produce images more or less instantaneously, but longer exposures reveal the inherent temporality of this process, showing us something that is clearly based on the world, yet quite different from our experience of it. Today, the ability to create images is so commonplace, of course, that we easily take it for granted, but early commentaries on photography reveal just how extraordinary it once was. Indeed, the history of photography provides both a compelling example of the power of representation, and a useful parallel to more recent forms of technological magic, especially that of machine learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the Perils of Automated Face Recognition</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/face-recognition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:59:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/face-recognition/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Bertillon,_Alphonse,_fiche_anthropom%C3%A9trique_recto-verso.jpg">&lt;img src="../../img/face-recognition/bertillon.jpeg"
alt="Anthropometric data sheet (both sides) of Alphonse Bertillon (1853–1914)."/>&lt;/a>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Anthropometric data sheet (both sides) of Alphonse Bertillon (1853–1914).&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For anyone who has been paying attention, it will not have gone unnoticed that the past year has seen a dramatic expansion in the use of face recognition technology, including at schools, border crossing, and interactions with the police. Most recently, &lt;a href="https://news.delta.com/delta-unveils-first-biometric-terminal-us-atlanta-next-stop-detroit">Delta announced&lt;/a> that some passengers in Atlanta will be able to check in and go through security using only their face as identification. Most news coverage of this announcement emphasized the supposed convenience, efficiency, and technical novelty, while underplaying any potential hazards. In fact, however, the combination of widely available images, the ability to build on existing infrastructure, and a legal landscape that places very few restrictions on recording, means that face recognition represents a unique threat to privacy that should concern us greatly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What everyone needs to know about interpretability in machine learning</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interpretability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 20:46:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/interpretability/</guid><description>For anyone who’s been paying attention, it should be apparent that statistical machine learning systems are being widely deployed for automated decision making in all kinds of areas these days, including criminal justice, medicine, education, employment, policing, and so on. Particularly with the recently enacted GDPR&amp;mdash;the new European regulation about data and privacy&amp;mdash;there is growing interest in having systems that are interpretable, that is, we can make some sense of why they are making the prediction that they are making. To borrow an example from Been Kim, if a computer tells you that you need surgery, you’re probably going to ask for some sort of explanation.</description></item></channel></rss>