<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open-Science on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/open-science/</link><description>Recent content in Open-Science on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:18:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/open-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Credible Estimates and Open Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/blair-institute/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 20:18:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/blair-institute/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somewhere on social media I encountered the recent story that the &lt;a href="https://www.institute.global/">Tony Blair Institute for Global Change&lt;/a>, (a large, avowedly centrist think tank created by Tony Blair), put out a &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240709092248/https://assets.ctfassets.net/75ila1cntaeh/45YsrTDwevNRvsTsZ5dZGS/fc9805fa3a5a1de3c931d0446dcec239/Tony_Blair_Institute_for_Global_Change__The_Potential_Impact_of_AI_on_the_Public-Sector_Workforce__July_2024.pdf">report&lt;/a> estimating the potential impact of AI on jobs in the public service, but that ironically, they arrived at their estimates by basically just asking GPT-4. While this does have a certain kind of poetry to it, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly what we think of as a reputable methodology.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>University of Michigan's New AI Tools</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/michigan-gpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 21:04:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/michigan-gpt/</guid><description>Just before the start of the fall semester, the University of Michigan announced that it was launching a new suite of tools, all focused on &amp;ldquo;generative AI&amp;rdquo;, (although so far limited to language models), which will be available to all students, faculty, and staff. This post provides a preliminary exploration of the new offerings.</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT Dominance</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/chatgpt-dominance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 14:39:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/chatgpt-dominance/</guid><description>&lt;p>I expect that almost anyone reading this will have heard of ChatGPT by now. Released about a month ago, ChatGPT is a system developed by OpenAI which provides text responses to text input. Although details are scarce, under the hood ChatGPT is basically a large language model, trained with some additional tricks (see Yoav Goldberg&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/yoavg/59d174608e92e845c8994ac2e234c8a9">write up&lt;/a> for a good summary). In other words, it is a model which maps from the text input (treated as a sequence of tokens), to a distribution over possible next tokens, and generates text by making repeated calls to this function, and sampling tokens from the predicted distributions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reproducibility in Art and Science</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 20:43:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/reproducibility-in-art-and-science/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marking the beginning of a new &lt;a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2017/may/30/rhizome-google-partnership/">partnership&lt;/a> between Rhizome and the Google Cultural Institute, the Rhizome blog recently published a &lt;a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2017/may/30/preservation-by-accident-is-not-a-plan/">conversation&lt;/a> between Dragan Espenschied, Rhizome’s preservation director, and Vint Cerf, Google’s Chief Internet Evangelist. In addition to bringing together two people with among the coolest job titles ever, it got me thinking about some similarities between art and science when it comes to the issue of reproduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main thrust of the conversation is about the difficulty of preserving internet art. In particular, works such as &lt;a href="https://anthology.rhizome.org/the-web-stalker">The Web Stalker&lt;/a> were often made in a particular context, intended to be performances of a sort, and which depended on the existence of a certain technical infrastructure, including a particular operating system, a particular input device, an internet connection, and accompanying protocols. Part of the conversation relates to the fact that it’s actually very difficult to maintain or recreate every single thing that is required in order for a modern viewer to have the exact same experience as when it was first created. Nevertheless, Dragan argues, there is still value in preserving part of the experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>