<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in Data on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 19:48:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samsung's Encounter with ChatGPT</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/samsung-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 19:48:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/samsung-chatgpt/</guid><description>As ChatGPT continues to ricochet through the news cycle, media outlets are surely on the hunt for new angles they can present to the public in order to keep this story in motion. Among other threads, one that has gained some traction is the question of risks to privacy and security presented by these new systems.
Last week, a number of US outlets reported on data leaks at Samsung, in which three employees (in separate incidents) apparently entered confidential company information into ChatGPT.</description></item><item><title>Counting Deaths</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/counting-deaths/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 17:24:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/counting-deaths/</guid><description>Although morbid, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to read a recent article in the NYT about efforts in Sierra Leone to use &amp;ldquo;electronic autopsies&amp;rdquo; in a large scale attempt at counting deaths. According to the article, this undertaking is part of a broader effort at data collection, including questions on age, religion, marital status, etc. The novelty, it seems, is in trying to be thorough with respect to what people have died of (including extensive questions about symptoms), even though this information is being collected potentially long after the fact.</description></item><item><title>AI Dermatology: Part 1</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 07:32:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/ai-dermatology-1/</guid><description>Midway through last year Google announced a new foray into the medical technology space, sharing that it was developing an &amp;ldquo;AI-powered dermatology assist tool&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;a phone-based app that would allow users to take photos of skin lesions and retrieve information about relevant medical conditions from the web. Similar apps already exist, but it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that a comparable effort by Google is likely to have much more significant effects on how people interact with the medical system, their personal data, and even their own bodies.</description></item></channel></rss>