<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ezra-Klein on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/ezra-klein/</link><description>Recent content in Ezra-Klein on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:42:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/ezra-klein/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Force of Law</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/force-of-law/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:42:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/force-of-law/</guid><description>I do not feel particularly well qualified to write about this, but it seems to me that recent events have dramatically and urgently gestured at the nature of the rule of law, and the tenuousness of reliable enforcement. Since coming into office, the new administration has been carrying out actions that many legal experts suggest are illegal. In several cases since then, judges have issued orders which demand a pause on particular actions. Most recently, the New York Times reports that a judge has now ruled that the White House has failed to comply with a court order. While less splashy than various overt actions, this kind of failure act seems to me like to very close to the red line suggested by various commentators, including conservatives.</description></item><item><title>Sociotechnical Considerations</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sociotechnical-considerations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 13:42:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/sociotechnical-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p>A whole genre of podcasts seems to have emerged recently, taking the shape of interviews with CEOs of AI companies, or similar. Although I have not listened to many of these, they mostly seem to be pretty abysmal, both because of the amount of hype they involve, and due to the lack of meaningful specifics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, of the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, the recent &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/12/podcasts/transcript-ezra-klein-interviews-dario-amodei.html">interview with Dario Amodei of Anthropic on the Ezra Klein Show&lt;/a> seems to me to be vastly better than the average. In part, this is because Klein is a smart, curious, and well informed interviewer, who asks a lot of the right questions, and pushes for details when responses get too mushy. In this case, it also helps that Amodei seems much more straightforwardly honest about limitations than most spokespeople in similar positions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>