<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>representation on Granular Material</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/representation/</link><description>Recent content in representation on Granular Material</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 21:27:37 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/tags/representation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Representational Power</title><link>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/representational-power/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 21:27:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dallascard.github.io/granular-material/post/representational-power/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/View_from_the_Window_at_Le_Gras">&lt;img src="../../img/representational-power//plate.jpeg"
alt="The original plate of “View from the Window at Le Gras”, a heliograph made by Nicéphore Niépce around 1827."/>&lt;/a>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>The original plate of “View from the Window at Le Gras”, a heliograph made by Nicéphore Niépce around 1827.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Although it isn’t normally thought of in these terms, taking a photograph involves recording a four-dimensional block of space-time and projecting it down to a two-dimensional representation. With sufficiently sensitive material (and a fast enough shutter), one can produce images more or less instantaneously, but longer exposures reveal the inherent temporality of this process, showing us something that is clearly based on the world, yet quite different from our experience of it. Today, the ability to create images is so commonplace, of course, that we easily take it for granted, but early commentaries on photography reveal just how extraordinary it once was. Indeed, the history of photography provides both a compelling example of the power of representation, and a useful parallel to more recent forms of technological magic, especially that of machine learning.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>